Good morning everyone.Now whether you're going to university to study business or some other subject,
大家早上好。现在，无论你们是在大学中学习商业还是其他专业，
many of you will eventually end up working for a company of some kind.
最后你们中的许多人都会去一些公司上班。
Now,when you first start working somewhere you will realise that the organisation you've joined has certain characteristics.
当你刚开始在某家公司工作时，你会发现你加入的这家公司有某些特征。
And we often refer to these social characteristics as the culture of the organisation
我们经常把这些社会特征称为公司文化。
this includes its unwritten ideas,beliefs,values and things like that.
它们包括一些不成文的想法、理念、价值等等。
One well known writer has classified company cultures by identifying four major types.
一位知名作家将公司文化分为四个主要类型。
The first type is called the Power Culture,and it's usually found in small organisations.
第一种是权力文化，经常出现在小公司里。
It's the type of culture that needs a central source of power to be effective,
这种文化需要权力的中央来源是有效的，
and because control is in the hands of just one or two people there aren't many rules or procedures.
因为控制权只在一、两个人的手中，所以没有很多规则或程序。
Another characteristic is that communication usually takes the form of conversations rather than, say, formal meetings or written memos.
另一种特征通常是对话形式的交流，而不是正规的开会或写备忘录。
Now one of the benefits of this culture is that the organisation has the ability to act quickly,
这种文化的优点是公司有迅速作出反应的能力，
so it responds well to threat,or danger on the one hand,and opportunity on the other.
所以它可以及时应对威胁、危险或机遇。
But on the negative side,this type of organisation doesn't always act effectively,
但是消极的一面是这类公司不能总是有效的做出行动，
because it depends too much on one or two people at the top, and when these people make poor decisions there's no-one else who can influence them.
因为它太依赖于顶层的一、两个人，当这些人做出错误的选择时，没有人能左右他们。
And the kind of person who does well in this type of business culture is one who is happy to take risks, and for whom job security is a low priority.
在这种公司文化里做得好的人是那种乐意冒险，对工作保障考虑较靠后的人。